Ziyang Jin

Station Manager Flight Dispatcher **Phone:** (+1) 617-615-9553

(+86) 181-4190-1016

Email: jinziyang55@outlook.com

Airlines Station Manager with 5+ years of experience in flight control, station operation management in Skytrax 5star Hainan Airlines in China and United States. CAAC Flight Dispatcher License Holder. Fluent English and native Mandarin speaker.

EDUCATION

Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics, Nanjing, Jiangsu, China Bachelor of Engineering in Air Transportation

Sept 2012-June 2016

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Hainan Airlines, Las Vegas/Boston/Los Angeles, United States Station Manager

Aug 2019-Present

- Supervise the overall management and assignment of flights to be operated including GHA functions, key
 performance indicator, training and development. Ensure the ground handling and ramp operation
 conform to the safety and security standards.
- Plan, organize and manage all activities related to the day-to-day activities of the Station Operation Department.
- Oversee the ramp handling activities in liaison with GHA, Caterers, Fuelling, Maintenance, Cargo, and Crew to expedite departure.
- Identify and resolve the service and operational issues. Handle the flight disruptions impacted by aircraft swaps, flight delays, cancellations and any other factors may affect the operation.
- Manage relationships with internal and external stakeholders and work collaboratively with local airport and civil aviation authority.

Hainan Airlines, Beijing, China

Flight Dispatcher

July 2016-July 2019

- Exercise the operational control on a co-authority basis with the Pilot-In-Command and for the joint responsibility of the safe and efficient planning and monitoring of a flight.
- Issue the Operational Flight Plans in accordance with the Aircraft Operating Manual, Flight Operations Manual and governing regulations.
- Perform the Flight Watch, analyse operational conditions and identify any opportunities that may impact
 operational capabilities, including weather, Air Traffic Control, aircraft performance, airports, runways,
 airways and navigational aids.
- Communicate to Air Traffic Control Services on all Operational Flight Plan requirements.
- Interpret the flight and field condition reports to provide flight crews with the latest operational information.